(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T13:37:09.241552",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みなさま 本日は
Everyone, today,
ビビ生誕祭2026にお越しくださいまして
thank you so much for joining us for Bibi's Birthday Live 2026,
誠にありがとうございます！
truly, thank you!
開演に先立ちまして
Before the show begins,
皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
we have a few requests and announcements for everyone.
本配信は一部収録もございますが 生配信部分もございますので
While part of this stream is pre-recorded, there will also be live segments,
いっぱいコメントやポストをして
so please comment and post a lot
たくさん盛り上げててください！
and get super hyped up!
みんなコメント見えてるよー！
I can see everyone's comments!
本配信のハッシュタグは
The hashtag for this stream is
ビビ生誕祭2026です。
#BibiBirthdayLive2026.
ライブの感想などSNSでたくさんポストして盛り上げてください！
Please post your thoughts on the live on SNS and hype it up!
開演中 カメラやスマートフォンなどによる写真撮影は大歓迎です！
During the show, taking photos with cameras or smartphones is very welcome!
たくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいましたら めちゃめちゃ嬉しいです！
If you post a lot and hype things up, I'll be super happy!
それでは 開演まで 今しばらくお待ちください。
Now then, please wait just a little longer until the show begins.
皆さま 本日は、「Vivi生誕祭2026」にお越しくださいまして誠にありがとうございます。
Everyone, thank you very much for coming to the "Vivi Birthday Festival 2026" today.
開演に先立ちまして、皆さまにお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Before the show begins, I have a few requests and announcements to share with you all.
本配信は一部収録もございますが、生配信部分もございますので、
This broadcast includes some pre-recorded segments, but also live parts,
いっぱいコメントやポストをして、たくさん盛り上げてください！
so please send lots of comments and posts to make it super exciting!
コメントも全部見えてるよ！
I can see all your comments too!
本配信のハッシュタグは「Vivi生誕祭2026」です。
The hashtag for this broadcast is #ViviSeitansai2026.
ライブの感想などSNSでめちゃくちゃたくさんポストしてください！
Please post your thoughts on the live stream and everything else on SNS like crazy!
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどでの写真撮影は、大歓迎です！
During the show, taking photos with cameras or smartphones is very welcome!
たくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいますとVivi大歓喜です！
If you post a lot to hype it up, Vivi will be overjoyed!
皆さん！Viviと楽しむ準備できてますかー！？
Everyone! Are you ready to have fun with Viviー!?
おい！Viviめちゃ緊張してるよ！みんな震えるほどの膝を支えてくれ、口も回らなくなってきた。
Hey! Vivi is super nervous! Everyone, support my shaking knees, my mouth is starting to stumble.
うっ、えっ、でもViviにメロメロになる準備できてますかー！？
Uh, eh, but are you ready to fall head over heels for Viviー!?
あ、そっかみんな、もうでもすでにViviにメロメロか。
Ah, right, everyone, well, you're already head over heels for Vivi anyway.
今日はアイドル全開のViviを目に焼き付けてな？たくさんかわいいって言って！
Today, burn fully idol Vivi into your eyes, okay? Say "cute" a lot!
かわいい？知ってるー！
Cute? I knowー!
それでは開演まで今しばらくお待ちください。
Well then, please wait a little longer until the show starts.
ねぇなんだろな もう本当にこの私がいるのに
Hey, I wonder why, even though I'm really right here,
誰よりも君のことを思ってる人がこんなにも近くにいるんだけどな
someone who cares about you more than anyone else is so close by, you know.
よしこうなったら揃り揃り踏み込みます
Alright, if it comes to this, I'll step in nice and slowly.
ちゅびどぅび あゆれでぃ ごー
Chubi dubi, are you ready, go!
ねぇこの後予定とかあるの？
Hey, do you have any plans after this?
帰り道も一緒でしょ？そういえば
We're going home the same way, right? Come to think of it,
今日髪の分け目変えたんだよ 気づいてる？
I changed how I part my hair today, did you notice?
あ、でもない
Ah, never mind.
デートの予定とか使ってもあんまり実感ないな
Even if we talk about date plans, it doesn't feel very real.
どうなんだろ これそうだなってなくないのかな
I wonder how it is, is it really not like that?
なんて妄想 私の方なんじゃないのかな
Such delusions, isn't it actually on my end?
周りにねうつりしないで よわってしちゃって
Don't get distracted by your surroundings, getting all weak.
I want you なんとなく少しでも一緒にいたいんだけど
I want you, somehow I want to be together even just a little bit.
I need you ねぇねぇそろそろ気づいちゃってるんじゃない？
I need you, hey hey, aren't you starting to realize it by now?
カウントダウンしてね もうこっち向いて
Count down, hey, look over here already.
茶々茶 今度デートに誘って大網大作戦バババ 打ち抜かれるエルを
Cha cha cha, invite me on a date next time, grand plan bababa, piercing arrows
ドキドキハートが点滅システム もーそのとき君と永遠に
Thumping heart blinking system, moo at that time forever with you
エンレスラブ あみき 誕生飛ばして満たす
Endless love amiki skipping birthdays and filling up
愛ときき まぎんたと ほらめを
Love and kiki maginta and look into my eyes
合わせてよ 指先まで教えてあげる
Match them up, I'll teach you right down to my fingertips
恋と気づくまでのカウントダウン
The countdown until you realize it's love
目と目合わせてくらりくらり いつでも準備は出来てて
Eyes meeting, spinning and spinning, I'm always ready
触れ合えばもらくらく
If we touch, so comfortably
ねぇ ねぇ 私だけ見ててね 絶対！
Hey, hey, look only at me, okay? Promise!
せーのっ！
Ready, set!
頭のてっぺんから決まるモチベーション
Motivation starts right from the top of my head
視覚 嗅覚 言語の3つで人の印象は決定します
Sight, smell, and language—these three determine one's impression
甘っことなくちゃ、今日も可愛いでしょう？
Without being too sweet, I'm cute today too, right?
ヘイヘイ！ ハリウッドショータイム
Hey, hey! Hollywood showtime!
さぁ キミだけのワンタイム
Now, your one-and-only one time
石畳 いちご一会に 感触 センサー 感じる エネルギー
Cobblestones, a once-in-a-lifetime touch, sensing energy
髪を整え 私が可愛いから シークレットパフォーマンス
Fixing my hair because I'm cute—a secret performance!
ただ行こう あまり実感ないな
Let's just go, though it doesn't feel quite real yet
どうなんだろ これけど実際 まだ振り向いてくれたら
I wonder how it is... but if you actually turn around,
いいさいいさ けど問題ない
That's fine, that's fine, but no problem!
まったく不器用なんだから
You're so clumsy after all,
少しはスノーになって
So be a little more smooth...
ねぇ、これじゃ泣けちゃう
Hey, this is gonna make me cry
ワンツードクター仕立て 最善から見ててほしいな
Styled like a one-two doctor, I want you watching from your best angle
ねぇねぇ ぼちぼち分かっちゃってるんじゃない？
Hey, hey, don't you already realize it by now?
さぁ キュンとして 萌えっ もう勝ち気てよ
Now, get fluttery, get moe, and let's win this!
ちゃっちゃかちゃったキミに ピース 感 が ガケヒキデノレイザータッチ
To you, brisk and snappy, with a sense of peace, a laser touch at the edge
気づけば 距離 時間 ついて
Before I knew it, distance and time caught up
ドキドキ ハートが テンパイしてる もういっそのこと私永遠に
My heart is pounding like crazy, so why don't you keep me forever?
Happiness love あのキミを 独占して示す愛
Happiness love, monopolize that you and show my love
あったはずだった ほらまた 眠れないよ
It should've been there, see, I can't sleep again
指折り 数えて 教えてあげる
Counting on my fingers, I'll teach you
恋に気付くまでの 簡単な
It's so simple until you realize you're in love
嘘だな どうだいもっとくらって
That's a lie, how about taking more?
前髪の無神経 主人公感 とまないよね
The dense bang vibe doesn't stop, does it?
もう我慢ならない 分かりやすく参ります
I can't hold back anymore, I'm coming clean and clear!
準備はいいかい？ ゴー！
Are you ready? Go!
ちょっと強がりで テレくさくて
A little bit put-on, acting tough, feeling shy,
でも止まれないの
But I can't stop!
いつかをお待ち続けたいよ
I want to keep waiting for "someday"
私を見ててね
Please keep watching me!
Happiness love あのキミの 感情独占して満たす愛
Happiness love, love that monopolizes and fulfills your emotions
あったはずだった ほらねえは 合わせてよ
It should''ve been there, see, match your "nee" with mine!
指先なぞって 教えてあげる
Tracing your fingertips, I'll teach you
恋に気付くまでの 簡単な
It's so simple until you realize you're in love
ネット 目合わせ 蔵なくなり いつでも準備はできててね
Eyes locking online, getting dark, I'm always ready
触れ合えば 目くらくなり 今すぐ抱きしめて
If we touch, I get dazzled, hug me right now!
私だけ見ててね 絶対！
Look only at me, okay? Promise!
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 今日はどこに行こうかな？
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ふたりの思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, piling up our memories
眩しくて目が覚めた日は ちょっとだけきもちいい 眠いけどせっかくだし キミはもう起きてるかな？
The dazzling day I woke up to feels a little bit good. I'm sleepy, but since I'm up, are you already awake?
今日の予定を勝手にたてるの
I'm making our plans for today all by myself
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 今日はどこに行こうかな？
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ふたりの思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, piling up our memories
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 明日はどこに行こうかな？
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going tomorrow?
キミといると行き先はどこも特別に変わるの 信号が青に変われば あとはこの先にまってるのは広い海
If I'm with you, any destination turns into something special. If the traffic light turns green, waiting for us beyond this point is the vast sea
海岸を沿うように駆ける いつもの音楽をBGMにして
Racing along the coastline, making our usual music the BGM
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 今日はどこに行こうかな？
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ふたりの思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, piling up our memories
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 明日はどこに行こうかな？
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going tomorrow?
キミといると行き先はどこも特別に変わるの ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 今日はどこに行こうかな？
If I'm with you, any destination turns into something special. Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ふたりの思い出を重ねて ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 明日はどこに行こうかな？
Hey, hey, hey, hey, piling up our memories. Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going tomorrow?
キミといると行き先はどこも特別に変わるの キミといると いう奇跡は そこをそっと 平熱に変わるの
If I'm with you, any destination turns into something special. The miracle of being with you gently turns into a normal warmth there
信号が青に変われば あとはこの先にまってるのは広い海
If the traffic light turns green, waiting for us beyond this point is the vast sea
海岸を沿うように駆ける いつもの音楽をBGMにして
Racing along the coastline, making our usual music the BGM
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 今日はどこに行こうかな？ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ふたりの思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going today? Hey, hey, hey, hey, piling up our memories
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 明日はどこに行こうかな？ キミといると行き先はどこも特別に変わるの
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where are we going tomorrow? If I'm with you, any destination turns into something special
信号が青に変われば あとはこの先にまってるのは広い海
If the traffic light turns green, waiting for us beyond this point is the vast sea
海岸を沿うように駆ける あとはこの先に待ってるのは広い海
Racing along the coastline, waiting for us beyond this point is the vast sea
さあ！行こう 光る未来へ
Now, let's go toward the shining future!
ホラ 夢を連れて
Bring dreams along with us,
ポケットにひとつ 勇気にはぎしり
stuffing courage into our pockets!
走り出したあの道
The road we started running down
虹色に輝いて
shines in rainbow colors,
ココロの地図をいろどる
coloring the map of our hearts.
クールな私 キラキラな私
A cool me, a sparkly me,
大空に描いてみれば
if I try painting them across the vast sky—
白いシャツ 風なびき
White shirt fluttering in the wind,
飛べるよどこまでも
I can fly anywhere!
たまには泣き虫の雲
Sometimes a cloud of worries appears,
太陽が笑い飛ばす
but the sun laughs them away.
仲間だって時にはライバル
Companions sometimes become rivals,
真剣勝負よ！
it's a serious showdown!
Going my way(Going my way)
Going my way (Going my way),
大志を抱き
holding high ambitions,
汗キラリ 涙こぼれても
even if sweat sparkles and tears spill,
立ち止まるな！
don't stop!
アイドル(アイドル) カツドウ(カツドウ)
Idol (Idol), activity (activity),
Go Go Let's go(Go Go Let's go)
Go Go Let's go (Go Go Let's go)!
明日に向かって
Head toward tomorrow
走り続ける
and keep running.
キミが見える
I can see you,
ファイトくれる
I can fight!
かすかに見えた 夢の先の景色
The scenery faintly seen beyond our dreams.
ブランコの放物線
The playground swing's clearance line
金色に瞬いて
twinkling in gold,
照らすよいつまでも
shining on forever.
ときにクールな逆風
Sometimes a cool headwind
追い風が笑い飛ばす
turns into a tailwind and laughs away.
向き合って戦って分かり合って
Facing each other, fighting, and understanding one another,
手をつないで
holding hands,
まっすぐ(みあげて) あおそら(歌うよ)
straight ahead (raising our sights), singing together,
Flying so high!(Flying so high!)
Flying so high! (Flying so high!)
希望の脊
On the crest of hope,
横切る七色 飛び出して風に乗れよ！
bursting across the rainbow colors, ride the wind!
Yes, let you go!(Yes, let you go!)
Yes, let you go! (Yes, let you go!)
向こう側へと
Heading to the other side,
ふみき る音は 旅立ちの合図
the sound of footsteps is the signal of departure,
ウタも弾む
and the song plays too.
走って(走って)
Running (running),
歩いて(歩いて)
walking (walking),
笑って(笑って)
smiling (smiling),
つま先と手と
tiptoes and hands,
踏みしめて 握りしめて今 ここにいるよ
stepping down and holding tight, we're here now!
アイドル(アイドル) カツドウ(カツドウ)
Idol (Idol), activity (activity),
Go Go Let's go!(Go Go Let's go!!)
Go Go Let's go!! (Go Go Let's go!!)
ゴールに向かって
Heading toward the goal,
走り続ける
keep running,
キミが見える
you can see it,
ファイトくれる
it will give you a fight!
だめだめだめ 脳みそのなかから「やめろ馬鹿」と渦巻くモラリティ
No, no, no, a moral panic swirling inside my brain,
ダーリン、ベイビー、ダーリン
darling, baby, darling,
半端なラブ！とキラキラ浮き足立つフィロソフィ
a half-baked love and a sparkling, footing philosophy.
しぬほどかわいい上目遣い
You're so cute when you look up from under,
何がし法に触れるくらい
enough to break the law.
ばらまく乱心、気付けばとうじゅん
Scattering distracted thoughts, before I knew it, I'm dazed.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
It's your fault for being born into this world.
やらたと心どい恋煩い
A messy, unstable romance,
バラバラなる頭とこの身体
a fragmented mind and body.
頸動脈から「I love you」が吹き出て
"I love you" gushes from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト
Iris Out!
いったいどうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
アバラの奥を ザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The Zayl melts deep inside the amber, making me want to puke.
瞳孔バチ開いておぼれ死にしそう
My pupils fly wide open, I'm about to pass out.
いまこの世で君だけ大せいいかい
Right now in this world, you're the only one I adore.
ダーリン、ダーリン、ダーリン、ダーリン
Darling, darling, darling, darling,
darling, darling, darling, darling.
ひっくりかえしても勝ち目がない
Even if you turn things upside down, I can't win.
君だけルールは適用外
You're the only exception to the rules.
よっつともオセロは黒しかしない
Even if we cross paths, zero is still black.
カタアゲホウダイ
Cut it out, let's play.
君が笑顔で放ったアバタケダブラ
An abatacept-abra-cada-bra-bra-bra,
デコにスティグマ、申し訳ねえな
sticking it on your forehead, I'm so sorry.
矢を刺して、貫いて、ここ弱点
Pierce with an arrow, pierce through, right here is the weak spot.
しぬほどかわいい上目遣い
You're so cute when you look up from under,
何がし法に触れるくらい
enough to break the law.
ばらまく乱心、気付けばとうじゅん
Scattering distracted thoughts, before I knew it, I'm dazed.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
It's your fault for being born into this world.
パチモンでもいい、なんでもいい
Patimon is fine, anything is fine,
いま君とナズいてるすべて欲しい
I want everything that is entangling with you right now.
頸動脈から「I love you」が吹き出て
"I love you" gushes from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト、アイリスアウト
Iris Out, Iris Out!
いったいどうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
アバラの奥を ザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The Zayl melts deep inside the amber, making me want to puke.
瞳孔バチ開いておぼれ死にしそう
My pupils fly wide open, I'm about to pass out.
いまこの世で君だけ大せいいかい
Right now in this world, you're the only one I adore.
ダーリン、ダーリン、ダーリン、ダーリン
Darling, darling, darling, darling,
darling, darling, darling, darling.
立ちもんでもいい なんでもいい
Standpoint doesn't matter, anything is fine,
いま君となづいてるすべて欲しい
I want everything that is brushing against you right now.
頸動脈から「I love you」が吹き出て
"I love you" gushes from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト
Iris Out!
いったいどうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
アバラの奥を ザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The Zayl melts deep inside the amber, making me want to puke.
瞳孔バチ開いておぼれ死にしそう
My pupils fly wide open, I'm about to pass out.
いまこの世で君だけ大せいいかい
Right now in this world, you're the only one I adore.
ダーリン、ダーリン、ダーリン、ダーリン
Darling, darling, darling, darling,
darling, darling, darling, darling.
ハーイ、みんなー！あいさつします！
Hi everyone! Let's do our greeting!
せーの、うーん、ビビ！
Ready? Um... Bibi!
いつもキラキラなきららびびでーすわ！
I'm Kiralarabi-bi, always sparkling!
みんなー！ここまで3曲続けて披露させていただきまーすわ！
Everyone! We've performed three songs in a row right up to here!
カウントダウンラブね、アイリスハートとそれぞれビビどうやった？
Count Down Love, Iris Heart... how did you like each of us, Bibi?
かわいくてセクシーで、うーんヘルシーやった？
Was it cute, sexy, and... um, healthy?
はい、まあね、見たら分かるヘルシーセクシーキューティーのビビなんですけれども。
Yeah, well, as you can see, I'm the healthy, sexy, cute Bibi, but—
あっ、そうして、みんな！今情報が入りました！トレンド2位だって！みんなありがとう！
Oh, and everyone! News just came in! We're #2 on trending! Thank you everyone!
でもでもビビ1位になりたいの、1位になりたいな。
But still, Bibi wants to be #1, I really want to be #1.
ぜひですね、今日のハッシュタグは、ビビ生誕祭2026でめーちゃめちゃたくさんポストしまくってください！
So please, post a ton today with the hashtag #BibiBirthday2026!
かわいいビビをいっぱいスクショしてな！
Take lots of screenshots of cute Bibi!
はい、そして今回のですね、ライブのコンセプトは、まあ先ほども言ったように、キューティー、ヘルシー、うーん、セクシーの3つになってまーす！
Yes, and the concept for this live stream is, as I mentioned earlier, cuteness, healthiness, um, and sexiness—all three!
はい、雰囲気もね、テーマに合わせて、まあ変わってたんですけど、この舞台みんな気づいててたかな？
Yeah, the atmosphere also changed to fit the themes, but did everyone notice this stage?
はい、このあとね、楽曲もテーマに合わせて変化していくのでお楽しみにして！
Yes, the upcoming songs will also change according to the themes, so look forward to it!
あんなでかいステージに立ててビビ幸せものやー！みんなありがとう！
I'm such a lucky Bibi getting to stand on such a huge stage! Thank you everyone!
それでは次はゲストパートです！ゲストパートは収録なのですが…
Now then, next is the guest part! The guest part is prerecorded, but...
あんなことやこんなこともしちゃいむすよ！もう、やーらしっ！
We're going to do all sorts of things there too! Oh, how lewd!
胸ぐらを掴まれて 強烈なパンチを
Having my collar grabbed and taking a fierce punch,
食らってよろけて 肩を並べべたつく
staggering as I get hit, walking side by side, sticky and damp,
また見劣りの雨にお前はにやけて
you smirk in the inferior-feeling rain.
傷口が綺麗になるなんて嘘を吐く
You tell lies like "the wounds will heal up clean,"
いつも口喧嘩さえ うまくできないくせして
even though you can never even argue properly.
さあ泥だらけで 迷うなよ
Come on, covered in mud, don't get lost.
あまりのつまらなさに目が潤んだ
My eyes grew moist from sheer boredom.
何度も青臭さだけで涙を流して
Shedding tears time and time again out of sheer naivety,
不安定な心を肩に預け合いながら 腐りかけたバッドエンドに逆らう
leaning our unstable hearts on each other's shoulders, defying a rotting bad end.
なぜだろう歓びよりも心地よい 痛みがじりじりと響いて
I wonder why—a pain more pleasant than joy reverberates persistently,
濡れた服にしたうちしながら 晴れ上がったゴミ溜めで笑う
clicking my tongue at my soaked clothes, laughing in a cleared-up wasteland.
土砂降りの夜に誓ったり別れ 胸を抉るような言葉を
Swearing or parting on a pouring rainy night, saying words that gouge out the heart.
胸ぐらを掴み返して 反撃のパンチを繰り出すくらいじゃなきゃ お前の隣には立てないから
If I don't grab your collar back and throw a counter-punch, I can't stand by your side.
相手がなんであれ怯まない 何度殴られても諦めない
No matter who the opponent is, I won't flinch; no matter how many times I'm hit, I won't give up.
忘れるな 忘れるなと息をかせ続け
Panting and gasping, "Don't forget, don't forget."
すれ違って しくじって やり過ごして 離れたくて やり直して しくじって やり過ごして 肩を貸して
Passing each other by, messing up, letting it slide, wanting to get away, trying again, messing up, letting it slide, lend me your shoulder.
ああ 傘はいらないから 言葉を一つ作れないか
Ah, I don't need an umbrella, so can't we make up a single word?
ぬるい優しいさではなく 弱音を吐かされた 胸の奥をえぐるような言葉を
Not lukewarm kindness, but words that make me voice my weakness and gouge deep into my chest.
何度も青臭さだけで涙を流して…
Shedding tears time and time again out of sheer naivety...
流して
Flowing away...
うたかた心を形に預け合いながら
Entrusting this fragile heart to you as we share the time.
走り切ったバッドエンドに抗う
Running past the bittersweet end.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地より
Why is it that tears taste sweeter than joy,
痛み すすりと響いて
and resonate deeper than pain?
濡れた服に下打ちしながら 晴れ上がった顔に合せて笑う
Laughing with a flushed face in my wet clothes,
どしゃ降りの夜に
in the pouring rain.
囚われの秘密に 遠いかけるように
Like reaching out for the secrets of our ties,
光った瞳の中で 違ったり無事に
shining deep within our eyes.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire!
いいの？ 吸い付ちゃっていいの？
Is it fine? Is it fine if I bite?
「もう無理もう無理」なんては悪い子だね
"No more, no more," you say, in that bad boy way.
試したいな いっぱいではきたいな
I want to try it, throw up from too much.
まだ絶対いけるよ
I can definitely take more!
最低最高
The worst, the best,
ずっといき来してる
stuck here going back and forth.
「正味」ばかり 割り切れ切れないけど 余りじゃない
From night 'til the morning, there no more.
そっと朝まで通せんぼ 繰り返すgetYADA 我儘はタダ
Repeating the 'no, thank you's, selfishness free.
欲張ってまたチャンスを逃すのだ 病まない もしもし 叶えたいけど
Disease of saying 'what if's though I want it all to come true,
重なって押し潰されちゃうのかも
it might just pile up only to get crushed under the weight.
いいじゃん 楽しいじゃん 気持ちいいじゃん
Fine, right? It's fun, right? Feels good, right?
溺れるまでが癖になるね
Addicted to staying until I'm 'bout to drown.
絶叫
I scream!
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire!
いいの？ 吸い付ちゃっていいの？
Is it fine? Is it fine if I bite?
「もう無理もう無理」なんては悪い子だね
"No more, no more," you say, in that bad boy way.
試したいな いっぱいではきたいな
I want to try it, throw up from too much.
まだ絶対いけるよ
I can definitely take more!
きみもヴァンパイア
You, too, a vampire!
いいよ 吸い付ちゃっていいよ
It's fine. It's fine if you bite.
「もう無理もう無理」だって言わせて欲しい
"No more, no more," that phrase, make me say the same.
きみ以外では絶対にいけないよ
Anyone else but you will simply not be fine.
ほら絶賛させてよ
Hey, please give me your praise, too!
ナイショの想い 洗いざらい吐き出してみたら鳴り止まないばかり
Something that's always longed for, withering dry as is now.
わりきれないけど あまりじゃない
How many times is this?
そっと朝まで通せんぼ 踏み崩すような ご都合守魔はただ
Inside all of the foam where it's like we can see the stars.
きみもヴァンパイア
You, too, a vampire!
ねえ 楽しいじゃん 気持ちいいじゃん 溺れるまでがくせになるね
Please give me just a chance, I can definitely take more!
絶対いけるよ
I can definitely take more!
きみもヴァンパイア
You, too, a vampire!
ねえ 楽しいじゃん 気持ちいいじゃん 溺れるまでがくせになるね
Please give me just a chance, I can definitely take more!
絶対いけるよ
I can definitely take more!
きみもヴァンパイア
You, too, a vampire!
いいよ 吸い付ちゃっていいよ
It's fine. It's fine if you bite.
「もう無理もう無理」だって言わせて欲しい
"No more, no more," that phrase, make me say the same.
きみ以外では絶対にいけないよ
Anyone else but you will simply not be fine.
ほら絶賛させてよ
Hey, please give me your praise, too!
きみもヴァンパイア
You, too, a vampire!
いいよ 吸い付ちゃっていいよ
It's fine. It's fine if you bite.
「もう無理もう無理」だって言わせて欲しい
"No more, no more," that phrase, make me say the same.
きみ以外では絶対にいけないよ
Anyone else but you will simply not be fine.
ほら絶賛させてよ
Hey, please give me your praise, too!
求めちゃってまた枯らしちゃって今何回目？
How many times is this?
星が見えるような泡の中で
Inside all of the foam where it's like we can see the stars.
きみもヴァンパイア
You, too, a vampire!
延長をください まだ絶対いけるよ
Please give me just a chance, I can definitely take more!
きみもヴァンパイア
You, too, a vampire!
まずはこっちおいで
First, come over to me.
絶対いけるよ
I can definitely take more!
ねえあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
きみがひとり 「xx」してるの知ってるよ
You're doing it alone, I know.
ビクンビクン震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Shaking and trembling, your voice is leaking out.
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてんだし言っちゃえよ効いてんの？
To be honest, it's pretty obvious, you know?
普通普通恥ずかしい？ みんな隠しているだけ
Everybody's hiding it, aren't they?
モニタリング
Monitoring
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to pester me,
ダーリン、あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to what I say at all
あれほど要りませんって言った煙草もお酒も
I've told you so much to stop smoking and drinking
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
Everyday two packs and seven cans without fail
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても看病してあげないんだから
Even if your liver is damaged, I won't nurse you
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
なぐさめさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake, with love's talent
泣いてくれなきゃ 彼氏失格 濡れていたいね いいでしょ
If you don't cry, you're disqualified as a boyfriend. I want to be soaked, alright?
なめとって飲み干したいんだってだってば
I want to lick it up and drink it all down, datteba!
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
手を伸ばして シェイクシェイク なんて最高ね
Reach out your hand, shake shake, how amazing
分けてくれなきゃ 君が痛いと 感じてたいね いいでしょ
If you don't share, I want to feel your pain, alright?
吸い取って救いたいんだってだってば
I want to suck it up and save you, datteba!
行きたいところからやりたいことまで 決めてる癖してだんまりさん
From where you want to go to what you want to do, you're Mr. Silence who decides everything
ねえ、そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない？ そうじゃない？
Hey, isn't that like an idiot? Isn't that right?
言いたいことがあるならさっさと言えば？
If you have something to say, why don't you say it?
ねえ、私知ってるよ
Hey, I know,
君が一人悔しがってんの知ってるよ
I know you're vexed all by yourself
突貫突貫高まるじゃん 君は押すことをやめない
Charging forward, it builds up, you never stop pushing
ねえ、私知ってるよ 君はできるこ知ってるよ
Hey, I know, I know you can do it
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
名前を呼んでよ インスタントで出会いに感情
Call my name, instant emotions at meeting
君は一人だだから歌って 一人じゃないもういいでしょ
You're all alone, so sing. You're not alone anymore, is that alright?
ソロプレイはおしまい なんだかんだってば
Solo play is over, datteba!
君がやめるときも 私そばにいるわ そうよ
Even when you stop, I'll be right by your side, that's right
いつも見守っているわ そうよ
I'm always watching over you, that's right
怖くないのよ
It's not scary
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
なぐさめさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake, with love's talent
泣いてくれなきゃ 彼氏失格 濡れていたいね いいでしょ
If you don't cry, you're disqualified as a boyfriend. I want to be soaked, alright?
なめとって飲み干したいんだってだってば
I want to lick it up and drink it all down, datteba!
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
手を伸ばして シェイクシェイク なんて最高ね
Reach out your hand, shake shake, how amazing
分けてくれなきゃ 君が痛いと 感じてたいね いいでしょ
If you don't share, I want to feel your pain, alright?
吸い取って救いたいんだってだってば
I want to suck it up and save you, datteba!
ねえ 私知ってるよ 君が一人悔しがってんの知ってるよ
Hey, I know, I know you're vexed all by yourself
ぐすんぐすんへこんでた弱音人からいんだない
Sobbing and depressed, hearing weak words from people...
汗が切れるまで一緒かすもっと泣いてたってなんだってだって受け止めてあげる もう我慢しないで出してだってば
Running until sweat dries, staying together...
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to pester me,
おねがいダーリン
Please, darling
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to what I say at all
あれほど要りませんって言った煙草もお酒も
I've told you so much to stop smoking and drinking
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず肝臓やられて...
Everyday two packs and seven cans without fail...
言いたいことは言わないの
You won't say what you want to say
行きたいところからやりたいことまで決めてる癖して
From where you want to go to what you want to do, you've already decided
ねえ そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない?
Hey, isn't that like an idiot?
いつも思わせぶりな感じで 察してほしい感じで
With a teasing vibe always, wanting me to guess
わざと口にしないの ずるくない?
Not putting it into words on purpose, isn't that unfair?
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen, what I want is a shapeless thing
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you, look and listen, peek deep in my eyes
真っ直ぐ見つめて おねだりしてみて
Gaze straight ahead, won't you pester me?
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷり
I've gazed at you so gallantly, yet now you completely pretend not to know
ていうかそれって胡坐かいてるだけなんじゃないですかぶっさいく
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels? How ugly.
舌先三寸 あなたのお陰で私のハートはボロボロです つれないときはつれないし
Thanks to your sweet talk, my heart is battered. When you're cold, you're cold.
ねえ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない? そうじゃない? じゃない? じゃない?
Hey, isn't that somewhat stupid? Isn't that right?
どこか足元見てる感じで 値踏みされてる感じで
Feeling like you're watching my feet, feeling appraised
駆け引きやり合い勝ち負けじゃない?
Is this not tactics and victory or defeat?
そういうめんどくさいことしてるから
'Cause you do such annoying things
無口なダーリン ねえ聞いて 切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Silent darling, hey listen, pain isn't a decoration
よそ見しないで 逃げないで 触ってよ 心の奥の方
Don't look away, don't run away, feel deep in my heart
一瞬のことじゃない おねだりしてはくれないの?
This isn't a momentary thing, won't you pester me?
言葉にできない怯えさは 強さやかさではないのよ
The cowardice you can't put into words isn't strength
甘えてないで 口に出してよ もうきちっとこっち向いとったら
Don't be spoilt, express yourself, face me already
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen, what I want is a shapeless thing
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you, look and listen, peek deep in my eyes
真っ直ぐ見つめて おねだりしてみてほしいの
Gaze straight ahead, I want you to pester me
おねだりして見て欲しいの ダーリン
Beg me and watch me, darling!
あなたはは私の言うこと全然聞かない
You never listen to a single thing I say.
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
Cigarettes and alcohol, which I told you to quit—
毎日二箱七杯一日たりとも欠かさず
two packs and seven drinks every single day without fail.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Even if your liver gives out and you kick the bucket,
看病してあげないんだから
I'm not going to nurse you back to health!
ああ言うやこう言う てこでもきかない
You make excuses and refuse to budge.
あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart is pitch black.
言いたいことは言わないし
You never say what you want to say,
ねえ そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない?
Hey, isn't that just ridiculous?
おねだり ダーリン
Please, darling!
やっと二人で歌えて
We can finally sing together!
めっちゃ嬉しいです!
I'm so, so happy!
いや、まずはこれを言わせろ、ピビ。
Wait, first let me say this, Pibi.
ん?
Hm?
お誕生日おめでとう。
Happy birthday!
やったー！おめでとー！
Yay! Happy birthday!
え、去年さ、びびトツ待ちしたじゃないですか。
Um, last year, Bibí, you waited for me on call, right?
え、してた?
Huh, did I?
え、覚えてないんか? おい! え、ピコラ行った?
What, you don't remember? Hey! Did Pekora go?
え、来てくれたやん! いたよね、いらびこだよね?
Eh, you came! You were there, right?
突然サプライズでマネージャーさんから、ピコラさんからプレゼントを...
Suddenly, as a surprise, from the manager and Pekora-san, a present was...
あ、そう! ああ、そうそう、覚えてない、覚えてない。
Ah, right! Oh, right, I remember.
いや、おめでとう、今年はほら! おい、忘れてんじゃんか!
Well, congrats, this has- Hey, you forgot, didn't you!
ディーディーディー、来たよー! おい、びびちゃんさ、
D-D-D, it's here! Hey, Bibí-chan,
そのプレゼント付けてきたのにさ、気づいてへんなってこう思ってさ。
even though I wore that present, you didn't notice at all.
いや、ヘアクリップ付けてたって今日入り。
Wait, you wore the hair clip today when you arrived!
いや、わかっててよ、いや、付けてくれてたなっていうふうに思ってたけど、それ恥ずかしがってやっぱ言えなかったのよ。
I knew you were wearing it, but I was too embarrassed to say so.
恥ずかしいじゃん、何もよ。
It's embarrassing, you know.
いや、でもそれが嬉しかったんですよ。だから去年に引き続きね、今年もこうやってピコラ先輩におめでとって言ってもらえて嬉しいです!ビビ大感激!
I'm so happy Pekora-senpai wished me a happy birthday again this year!
でもほら、もね、ビビちゃんとさ、二人で歌うのってなかなか無いことだからね。こう見てるね、
Singing with Bibí-chan just the two of us is pretty rare.
人も多分嬉しいペコなんじゃないかなって。ほんとにペコビビ最強!
I'm sure people are happy about it too. Seriously, PekoBibí is the strongest!
最強じゃん! ペコマリ最強! ペコマリ最強!
The strongest! PekoMari is the strongest! PekoMari is the strongest!
あー、ねえ、待って、何がペコマリ最強じゃん。また違くね? なんか噛み合ってなくね?
Wait, what do you mean PekoMari is the strongest? We're not on the same page at all!
あれあれ? あれあれ? また違うやん。もう違う。
Huh? Huh? That's totally different. Not again.
昨日で何歳になったの? いや、ビビはピチピチの22歳。
How old did you turn yesterday? Well, Bibí is a fresh, youthful 22!
22歳。あれ、前まで何歳だったんだっけ? あ、22歳です。
22. Wait, how old were you before? Ah, I'm 22.
22歳です。あ、まじか。
I'm 22. Ah, seriously?
なにが22歳るて。黙れよ。
What do you mean "22"? Shut up!
みそじの世界、突っ込めよ、お前も!
Roast the thirties, you too!
やだ、私とらない。みそじにならない。
No way, I won't age. I won't reach the thirties.
いや、鬼にならないかじゃないよ。みそじやめて、やめて! ならないよ。
Stop with the thirties, stop it! It won't happen.
なんて言うの? ペコビビの空気、え? なんかなあ、
What is this? PekoBibí's atmosphere?
毎日さ、ずっとさ、ビビのさ、なんか、え、今日受けてみたいなペコラ先輩。
You've been getting influenced by me, Pekora-senpai.
ギャルじゃん。ギャルにしないで、勝手に。
You're acting like a gal. Don't turn me into a gal!
え、だってマリンちゃんの影響受けたらどうなるんやっけ? エッチになる。
What happens if you get influenced by Marine-chan? You turn lewd.
なんでやねん! それでやんなよ。オーロライ度、これ以上エッチなメンバー増えたらあかんねん。
Why's that! We can't have any more lewd members!
てかさ、そんなこと言いながら、でも、ちょっと待って、この状況楽しんでるよね?
Besides, you're actually enjoying this situation, right?
あ、え? 楽しくねえし。
Ah, eh? Not at all!
楽しそうよ! 楽しそうだよ、お前は。
You look like you're having fun! You look so happy.
なんかさ、ビビを挟むことによって二人の新しいシナジーみたいなさ、
By sandwiching Bibí in between, it creates a new synergy...
なんかこの、なんていうの? あ、ね、ね、とな、あ、ダメだ、これは。
What is this? Ah, wait, no, this is bad.
7年目、7年目ね。7年間やってるとちょっと倦怠期みたいなさ。
Doing this for 7 years makes you feel burnt out.
あるからさ。え、でもピコラ、最近マリンのさ、聖なところ増えた。
Eh, but Pekora, recently Marine's saintly side has increased.
え? ちょっと待って、はい、ちょっと待って、これビビの聖者祭なんですか?
Wait, is this Bibí's Saint Festival?
どういうこと? ちょっと待って、何急になんですか、ペコラ先輩。
What do you mean? Wait, why all of a sudden, Pekora-senpai?
いや、なんかさ、もとからね、ポテンシャルも高いし、マリンってさ、もう、来たらすぐに空気変えてたやん、ペコビビの空気を。
You've always had high potential, and Marine changes the mood right away.
それもあるけど、7年目にして気づいたの。ね、7年目にして。
That's true, but I realized it in our 7th year.
ペコラはマリンの暴言が好きなん。
Pekora likes Marine's abusive language!
誰でもいいわけじゃないって。なんて言う!
It's not just anyone she likes. What are you saying!
いや、ほらうさぎ、このうさぎめ!
Well, you see, rabbit—you rabbit!
いや、なんか、熱が足りないよ、そんな。そんな熱がない。
No, there's not enough passion.
もっとうさぎめ! もっとみそじマリンちゃん!
More "you rabbit!" More "thirty-year-old Marine-chan!"
なんて言うねん! なんて言うねん! お前なあ!
What are you saying! You damn—!
いや、ビビちゃん、いよいよ今日誕生日だからさ、そう、誕生日なの。
Bibí-chan, since it's finally your birthday today, yeah.
ビビちゃんもさ、いよいよさ、MVP、MV-MVPって言ってたやん。
You kept saying you wanted to be MVP and all that, right?
だからさ、別にペコまりでも、ペコビビでもじゃなく、3人でMVPやればいい、ペコビビ。
So instead of just PekoMari, the three of us should just be MVP.
仲良くやる、真ん中にほら、真ん中にね。うまくやろう、ビビ。
Let's get along, right in the middle. Let's work it out well, Bibí.
っこまリ、イェーイ！
Kkomari, yay!
ねぇじゃあ、このMVってさ、
Hey, don't you think doing this MV...
なんか行く気やらなくない？ え？じゃあ、やろうぜ！
...is something we should do? Eh? Then let's do it!
なんかまんまやれって緊張するけど、でも嬉しい！
It's kind of nerve-wracking to do it like that, but I'm happy!
じゃあ、MVで！歌っていきまーす！
Then, in the MV! We'll start singing!
いぇーい！やったー！いぇーい！
Yay! Woohoo! Yay!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss,"
今 気づいた想い
my feelings that I just realized.
どんな言葉でも足りない
No matter what words I use, it's not enough,
から
so...
1, 2, 3, 4!
当たり前すぎるくらい
It's almost too obvious,
友達の時間が長かったせいで
since we've been friends for so long.
あなたのクセや性格だって
Your habits and personality,
他の子より知ってんの
I know them better than anyone else.
はー
Ha...
意地悪で恥ずかしがり屋な
You're such a teasing, shy guy,
あなたをもう待っていられないの
and I can't wait for you anymore!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss,"
今更「好き」なんて言葉より
which is more attractive than saying "I like you" now.
魅力的でしょ？
Right?
あなたにだけはそっと教えてあげる
I want to gently tell only you
胸の奥小さなつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the little bud deep in my heart.
時々甘えてみたり拗ねてみたり
Sometimes acting sweet or pouting,
そんな作戦らしくない
that's not like my usual strategy.
か弱きオトメじゃ勝てないの
A timid maiden won't win this way,
この恋だけは負けられない
I can't afford to lose this love.
はー 鈍感なあなたのこと
Ha, I want a clueless fellow
振り向かせたいから勝負かけるの
to notice me, so I'm taking a bet on you!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss,"
「愛してる」なんて言葉より
which is more attractive than saying "I love you."
魅力的でしょ？
Right?
聞こえちゃうくらい早くなるドキドキ
Can you hear my heart racing?
初恋はサイダーみたいに弾ける
First love sparkling like cider.
“友達同士”そんな境界線
A boundary line like "friendship,"
今すぐ飛び越えたいの
I want to jump over it right now.
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss,"
今更「好き」なんて言葉より
which is more attractive than saying "I like you" now.
魅力的でしょ？
Right?
聞こえちゃうくらい早くなるドキドキ
Can you hear my heart racing?
初恋はサイダーみたいに弾ける
First love sparkling like cider.
“友達同士”そんな境界線
A boundary line like "friendship,"
今すぐ飛び越えたいの
I want to jump over it right now.
友達同士そんな今日も偶然今すぐに飛び越えたいの
Friends like this, even today by coincidence, I want to jump over it right now!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss,"
今更「好き」なんて言葉より
which is more attractive than saying "I like you" now.
魅力的でしょ？
Right?
あなたにだけはそっと教えてあげる
I want to gently tell only you
胸の奥小さなつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the little bud deep in my heart.
感じて
Feel it.
せーの
One, two...
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's no good.
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
Look, it won't work.
こころは進化するよ もっと もっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
言葉にすれば 消えちゃう関係なら
If words will ruin our relationship,
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた
then we won't need them, or so I thought.
恐れてた だけど あれ?
Were you scared? But wait. Something's not right.
千里の道も一歩から
A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step.
石のようにかたい そんな意志で
With a resolution as firm as stone,
「し」抜きで いや 死ぬ気で！
working my fingers to the bone, no, putting my life on the line!
あなたが笑っている
When you're smiling,
それだけで笑顔になる
that alone brings a smile to my face.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's just a twist of fate,
巡り逢えたことが
finding you and meeting you
幸せなの
is such happiness.
でもそんなんじゃダメ
But that's no good,
もうそんなんじゃほら
no, really, look—
心は進化するよ もっともっと
our hearts are evolving, more and more!
そうそんなんじゃ
Yeah, like that—
ねえそんなんじゃ
hey, like that—
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
please keep looking at me, always and forever!
私の中のあなたほどあなたの
Within me, compared to you—
中の私の存在はまだまだ
my presence inside you is still so small,
大きくないこともわかってるけれど
and I know that full well, but...
今この同じ瞬間共有してる
at this very moment, sharing this instant together!
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ？
Dust builds up to make a traditional beauty?
クラクラり クラクラる あなたを見上げたら
Dizziness washing over me, when I look up at you,
それだけで眩しすぎて
just that is far too dazzling.
クラクラる クラクラり あなたを思っている
Dizzy and spinning, just thinking about you
それだけで溶けてしまう
is enough to make me melt away.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's just a twist of fate,
巡り逢えたことが
finding you and meeting you
幸せなの
is such happiness.
恋する季節は欲張りサキュレーション
The season of love is a greedy calculation!
恋する気持ちは欲張りサキュレーション
The feeling of love is a greedy calculation!
恋する瞳は欲張りサキュレーション
The eyes in love are a greedy calculation!
恋する乙女は欲張りサキュレーション
The maiden in love is a greedy calculation!
ふわふわり ふわわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ
Fluffy and fluttering, when you call my name,
それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
just that makes me float up into the sky.
ふわわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている
Fluttery and fluffy, when you're smiling,
それだけで笑顔になる
that alone brings a smile to my face.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's just a twist of fate,
巡り逢えたことが
finding you and meeting you
幸せなの
is such happiness.
でもそんなんじゃダメ
But that's no good,
もうそんなんじゃほら
no, really, look—
心は進化するよ もっともっと
our hearts are evolving, more and more!
そうそんなんじゃ
Yeah, like that—
ねえそんなんじゃ
hey, like that—
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
please keep looking at me, always and forever!
chAngE 馴染かない 流されないよ
chAngE—I won't be swayed, I won't be swept away,
今感じることに素直でいたいのか
I want to stay true to what I feel right now.
chAngE 何度でも生まれ変わるの
chAngE—I'll be reborn over and over,
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
embracing even my sadness as I start to run!
楽しい裏切りにあって
Encountering pleasant betrayals,
囚われない私(あたし)がここにいるの
untethered, I am right here.
足りない尽きないなんだって もっと歪ませてよ
It's not enough, it never ends—distort me even more!
パターン化したこんな世界じゃ
In such a patterned, repetitive world,
自分(じぶん)が誰なのか分からなくなる
I lose sight of who I really am.
枠にはまりたくないわ
I don't want to fit into any mold,
決めつけないでよ
so don't box me in!
道なき道を行くの
I'll walk down the pathless road—
そこにいたって待ってたって 何も始まらない
standing or waiting there won't make anything begin.
chAngE 馴染かない 流されないよ
chAngE—I won't be swayed, I won't be swept away,
今感じることに素直でいたいのだ
I want to stay true to what I feel right now.
誰かの思い通りにはさせないわ
I won't let things go just the way someone else wants!
chAngE 何度でも生まれ変わるの
chAngE—I'll be reborn over and over,
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
embracing even my sadness as I start to run!
あなたのもとには もう帰れないわ
I can never return to where you are anymore.
私は私らしく I wanna chAngE
I'll be my true self—I wanna chAngE!
chAngE
なびかない 流されないよ
I won't be bent and I won't be swept away.
今感じることに 素直でいたいの
I want to stay honest to how I feel now.
chAngE
何度でも 生まれ変わるの
I will be reborn, no matter how many times.
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
Embracing even my sadness, I'll run.
タノシカイ裏切りにあって
Encountering a surprisingly fun betrayal,
とらわれない私がここにいるの
I'm right here, unable to be captured.
足りない 尽きない なんだって
It isn't enough, it doesn't end...
もっと 歪ませてよ
Well, distort me more!
パターン化したこんな世界じゃ
In such a repetitive world as this,
自分が誰なのか分からなくなりそう
I sometimes lose sight of who I am.
枠にはまりたくないわ
I don't want to fit in the frames,
決めつけないでよ
so don't make my decisions!
道なき道を行くの
I'll walk down the pathless road.
そこにいたって 待っていたって 何も始まらない
Even if I stay here, even if I wait, nothing begins.
chAngE
なびかない 流されないよ
I won't be bent and I won't be swept away.
今感じることに 素直でいたいの
I want to stay honest to how I feel now.
誰かの思い通りにはさせないわ
I won't let it go the way someone wants it to.
chAngE
何度でも 生まれ変わるの
I will be reborn, no matter how many times.
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
Embracing even my sadness, I'll run.
あなたのもとにには もう帰れないわ
I can never return to you again.
私は私らしく I wanna chAngE
I'll be myself, I wanna chAngE.
chAngE
私が生変わった先にあなたがいるなら
If I am changed, will you be there?
あなたが変わった先に私がいるなら
If you are changed, will I be there?
chAngE
走り出すよ
I'll run.
chAngE
なびかない 流されないよ
I won't be bent and I won't be swept away.
今感じいることに 素直でいたいの
I want to stay honest to how I feel now.
誰かの思い通りにはさせないわ
I won't let it go the way someone wants it to.
chAngE
何度でも 生まれ変わるの
I will be reborn, no matter how many times.
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
Embracing even my sadness, I'll run.
ふたりで同じ景色が見れるなら
If I can see the same view with you,
あなたのもとにいつか帰りたいわ
I want to go back to you someday.
私は私らしく I wanna chAngE
I'll be myself, I wanna chAngE.
Luna say maybe
あのね。 I say “私、大丈夫?”
Hey, "I'm okay."
Maybe, うまくやれるはず
Maybe, it should go well.
ずっと走った 息継ぎもしないまま
Running continuously, without even catching my breath.
あっそう、終わりが来るなら
Ah, if an end is coming,
別に寂しくなんかないは
I don't particularly mind being lonely.
真実は心の奥の方
The truth is deep in my heart.
自分のことすら愛せないまま
Even without loving myself,
君のこと守れるのかな
can I protect you?
“信じて” どうか、
"Believe me," please.
正真正銘のこの思いを聴いて
Listen to this sincere feeling.
私、全身全霊で歌うから 大丈夫、
I'm singing with all my heart and soul, so it's okay.
世界はこんなに綺麗だと、
I know the world is so beautiful—
分かってる、分かってる、解ってる…
I know, I know, I understand...
分かってるよ!
I know it!
ごめんね。じれったい
Sorry, I'm being selfish.
足りない、こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
It's not enough; like this, I can't love anyone.
止めない、止まることは知らないの
I won't stop; I don't know how to stop.
言葉足らず、失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
Without words, I just lose things.
Luna say maybe...
降るのは、迷be, rainy
Falling is lost, be rainy.
愛せ、どんな自分でも
Love any self you are.
Navy色に染まるまで 時間はかかるかもしれないけど
It might take time to be dyed in navy blue,
I know, 輝くしかないこと
I know I can only shine.
ハイライト、塗り続けるしかない
Highlight, I have no choice but to keep painting.
真実はちゃんと、言わないとちゃね
The truth has to be spoken properly.
目に見えるものが続くっと、ずっと、そう、ずっと想いたい
I always want what is visible to continue.
君に、半信半疑な素振りして
Acting half-doubting with you,
心、空回り、遠回り
my heart misses the mark and goes far away.
最低だ、もう一回やり直せるのなら
It's the worst. If I could redo it,
素直になりたい、なりたい、なりたいと願ったジレンマ
I wished to be honest, honest, honest—a dilemma.
このまま、1人じゃ何もできない
Like this, I can't do anything alone.
全部、決めるのは、自分次第
Deciding everything is up to myself.
初めて背中をみた時に、覚悟を決めた。
When I saw my back for the first time, I resolved my determination.
どこまで いけるのか 届くのか わからないよ
I don't know how far I can go or if I can reach it.
怯懦が そこに立っている
Timidity is standing there.
3秒前バックステージ
3 seconds before backstage—
震える背中を君に預けて
Entrusting my trembling back to you.
この運命的出会いは きっと、そう、きっと
This fateful encounter is surely,
偶然みたいな
yes, surely like a coincidence,
多分、神様のいたずらです。
probably, it's God's prank.
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いが君の心(ところ)にちゃんと届くまで
Please, until this sincere feeling reaches your heart,
高らかに忠義をVermilion
High and loud, our loyalty to Vermilion
赤と黒の世界に旗を掲げ
Raising our flag in a world of red and black
聳え立つ城壁は漆黒のPride
The towering rampart is our jet-black pride
示そうか 迎撃するスーツのSoldiers
Shall we show it? Soldiers of the suit, meeting the onslaught
“歪んだ絶対”と侵略者達は言う
"A distorted absolute," the invaders call it
無印の白いカードひけらかし虚しきSophistry
Flaunting white cards of the unbranded, empty sophistry
“偉大な絶対”は存在にも気付かない
"The great absolute" doesn't even notice its own existence
無印よ、お前に価値はあるのか 張りぼての正義感
Unbranded one, do you have any worth? A makeshift sense of justice
全てを統べる者に相応しいMy lord 捧げる為生まれてきたんだと 生命が叫ぶ
As if born to be dedicated to the one who rules over all, my soul cries out
咲き誇れ堅牢なるVermilion
Bloom proudly, steadfast Vermilion
赤と黒の世界に旗を掲げ
Raising our flag in a world of red and black
茨纏う王国に真紅のFaith
Showing our crimson faith to the thorn-entwined kingdom
示すんだ 何者なのかを
What kind of person are we?
自己完結の人生じゃ 到底得られない意味があるさ
In a self-contained life, there is meaning that cannot possibly be attained
魂のスーツで 信じる自分を貫きWe are soldiers
With the suit of our souls, carry through the belief within us
“偉大な絶対”に忠義を 侵略者達は問う
Loyalty to the "great absolute," the invaders ask
飼われ従った対価は何かと
What is the price of being kept and obeyed?
幼ななPrejudice振りかざすほど 愚かしく
The more infantile prejudice is brandished, the more foolish it will be
そのうち分かるだろう
You will soon understand
規律を支える根底には 揺るがない愛国心
At the root supporting discipline is an unwavering patriotism
全てを染める大義に奮い発つMy soul
My soul awakens to the grand righteousness that dyes everything
惹かれるのは必然の理 色鮮やかなWorld
It is the inevitable law to be drawn to a vividly colored world
高らかに忠義をVermilion
High and loud, our loyalty to Vermilion
SexyドレスにあえてSneakers
In a sexy dress paired boldly with sneakers
夜でも派手に決める サングラス
Dressing up flashy even at night, sunglasses on
待ち合わせのBoysはHot Pink Suit
The boys we're meeting are in Hot Pink Suits
Do U wanna Party? 誰でもアリ
Do U wanna Party? Anyone is fine
どうせならテンションは全開だっけ
If we're gonna dream, let's go all out
いつでも楽しんでいたい
Because I always want to enjoy myself
たとえ上手く踊れなくても アタシとDance tonight
Even if I can't dance well, dance tonight with me
Are you Ready? Stand Up Baby, Rock Your Body
アタシらしくいたい 誰にもなれない! いつでもNice and Naughty
I want to be myself, no one else can be me! Always Nice and Naughty
輝けるかは自分次第
Whether you can shine depends entirely on you
Up and Down止めないでDJ
Up and Down, don't stop it, DJ
In and Out尽きるまで
In and Out, until it's all used up
Do or Don't遠慮しないで
Do or Don't, don't hold back
どうせ夢を見るならL Size カタログごと全部頂戴
If we're going to dream, let's take the L-size catalog and take it all
モチベーション上げて ワン・ツー ステップ Life is a party Come on everybody
Raise your motivation, one-two steps, Life is a party, come on everybody
ついて来るなら さあPut your hands Up
If you're gonna follow, come on, put your hands up
変わりたい 今すぐHurry up
Want to change, hurry up right now
お気に入りのShoes鳴らして 今夜もDance the Night
Ring your favorite shoes, dance the night away tonight too
Are You Ready? Stand Up Baby, Rock Your Body
つまらないデイズもう散々ね！
Boring days are already over!
奇蹟願っているだけの人生
A life just wishing for miracles,
watch me do...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without any tricks or secrets.
I wanna be free! だってまだ序盤だし
I wanna be free! Because I'm still starting out,
(The party ain't started)
Hey タクシー ちょっと宇宙迄
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit.
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔物のよう
The second hand ticks loudly like a monster urging the night.
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
Life is magic that melts away in an instant.
それならば駆け抜けて想い通り！
If so, run through it just as you wish!
おシャマな馬車飛び乗ってdrivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'.
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘のままに爛れに注意
Be careful not to get carried away by selfishness,
洒落た街でdancin'
dancing in a stylish city.
様々ならグッバイ劣等感
Say goodbye to all kinds of inferiority complex.
何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス
Someday, applause from the audience.
皆々御唱和あれ！
Everyone, join in!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
混濁がっても仕様が無い
even if it's chaotic, there's no other way.
ガラスシューズで踊る tonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight,
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
今夜に明日など無い
there's no tomorrow tonight.
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
So those who dance freely win, right?
dance！ラリラリホ
Dance! La la la li ho,
どんな問題も解は一つ
every problem has only one solution.
白紙も正解も間違いも愛す
Love blank papers, correct answers, and mistakes.
本物のあたしの理想
My true ideal.
なんだか世界は限界の気がして
The world somehow feels like it has limits.
ただただ安心じゃあ心配
Just being safe is worrying,
今すぐ jumpin out
jumpin' out right now!
chitty chitty bang bang
chitty bang bang
唯々諾々に危機感抱く日々に
In days when I feel an urgent crisis,
ぎりぎり爆発気味
explosive feelings are at their limit.
たった今発散してしまおうか
Should I let it all out right now?
まだまだヴィヴィアイ弾巧みに乱射
Still firing away skillfully,
一発じゃあ撃ち足りないわ
one shot is not enough.
ついに導き出した君にアンサー
Finally, I found the answer for you.
灰に成る迄踊って居ようぜ
Dance until it turns to ash.
おシャマな馬車飛び乗ってdrivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'.
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘のままに爛れに注意
Be careful not to get carried away by selfishness,
洒落た街でdancin'
dancing in a stylish city.
様々ならグッバイ劣等感
Say goodbye to all kinds of inferiority complex.
何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス
Someday, applause from the audience.
皆々御唱和あれ！
Everyone, join in!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
混濁がっても仕様が無い
even if it's chaotic, there's no other way.
ガラスシューズで踊る tonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight,
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
今夜に明日など無い
there's no tomorrow tonight.
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
So those who dance freely win, right?
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
混濁がっても仕様が無い
even if it's chaotic, there's no other way.
ガラスシューズで踊る tonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight,
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
今夜に明日など無い
there's no tomorrow tonight.
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
So those who dance freely win, right?
ふう…汗なんだてきまーす！
Whew... I'm sweating so much!
ふぅ、ただいまー！
Whew, I'm back!
みんな、ビビの初めてのオリジナルソロ楽曲、「ビビッドキュート」聴いていただきましたー！
Everyone, you've just listened to Vivi's very first original solo song, "Vivid Cute"!
どうだった？
How was it?
うん？よかった？かわいい？知ってるー！
Huh? It was good? Cute? I know!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
ということで、ちょっと新曲について詳しくご紹介したいなと思います。改めてタイトルは、「ビビッドキュート」です！じゃーん！
So, I'd like to introduce the new song in detail. Once again, the title is "Vivid Cute"! Ta-da!
うわ、なんだこの美少女！あ、ビビか。可愛すぎて一瞬誰か分からなかった！
Whoa, what a beautiful girl! Oh, it's me. She was so cute I didn't recognize her for a second!
はい、まあいつもかわいいんですけどもね！はい、えーこちらですね、え、可愛い女の子が、え、コスメで変身するような可愛い気持ちを、
Yes, well I'm always cute though! Yes, um, this is a song about a cute girl transforming with cosmetics.
歌にした楽曲になっております！はい、まあビビといえばメイク担当ですから、その時のワクワク感をね、思い出しながら歌っています！
It's a song capturing those adorable feelings! Since Vivi is in charge of makeup, I sang while remembering that excitement!
で、ミュージックビデオも、え、制作中なのでまた告知するから待っててね！
The music video is also being produced, so I'll announce it later, please wait for it!
そして、音源リリースは、本日24時からになります！みんな、たくさん聴いてねー！
And the audio release will be tonight at 24:00! Everyone, please listen to it a lot!
はい、そして、皆さんお待ちかね！ 「キキララビビ」誕生日記念2026年グッズが発売されます！
And now, everyone has been waiting for! "Kiki Lala Vivi" Birthday Commemoration 2026 merchandise is on sale!
はい、え、かわいい！ちょっとじゃあ早速一つ一つ見ていきましょう！
Yes, um, so cute! Let's check them out one by one right away!
1つ目は、こちら！ ビビとおやすみ抱き枕カバー！え、なんか、え、これこそ、やらしい、やらしいですよね！ビビ初の抱き枕カバーでーす！
First is this! "Vivi & Goodnight Dakimakura Cover"! Um, like, um, this is really, really suggestive, right? It's Vivi's very first dakimakura cover!
イラストはnoncoママに描いていただきました！気分に合わせて裏表で使ってください！2つ目は、こちら！ビビのめちゃかわ缶バッチ！
The illustration was drawn by nonco mama! Please use the front and back depending on your mood! Second is this! "Vivi's Super Cute Can Badge"!
3つ目は、こちら！ちぃビビぬいぐるみキーホルダー！はい、このね、ちぃビビついに、グッズ化となりました！4つ目は、こちら！ビビとおそろい推し活バッグ！
Third is this! "Chi-Vivi Plushie Keychain"! Yes, this, chi-vivi has finally become merchandise! Fourth is this! "Vivi & Matching Oshi-katsu Bag"!
ビビがいつも持ってるバッグをイメージした推し活バッグです！
An oshi-katsu bag inspired by the bag Vivi always carries!
ぬいぐるみを入れて持ち歩いてください！
Please put your plushie in and carry it around!
めちゃ可愛い、ビビとお揃いよ。
It's super cute, matching with Vivi.
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And the full-set purchase bonus is right here!
チェキ風ブロマイドカード！
A cheki-style bromide card!
こちらはですね、ビビの直筆サインと、箔押し複製メッセージが入ってます。
This features Vivi's handwritten signature and a foil-stamped replicated message.
メッセージの内容は、届いてからのお楽しみ！
The content of the message is a surprise until it arrives!
さらに特典ボイスもつきます。
It also comes with a bonus voice track.
タイトルは、「ベッドで一緒にゴロゴロしよう？」です。
The title is, "Wanna cuddle together in bed?"
ビビと二人でベッドで一緒にゴロゴロしている気持ちになれるシチュエーションボイスになってます。
It's a situation voice where you can feel like you're lounging in bed with Vivi.
みんなこれ絶対聞かないと。
Everyone definitely has to listen to this.
さあ、ここまで新曲告知とグッズ紹介でした！
Now then, that was the new song announcement and merchandise introduction!
この後は面会もあるからみんな絶対絶対遊びに来てね！
After this, there's a meet-and-greet too, so everyone please definitely come hang out!
何をやるかはまだお楽しみに。
What we'll be doing is still a surprise.
是非、まだの方はチャンネル登録と通知をオンにして、メン限の方にも入っていただき、アンコールも一緒に楽しめればと思います！
If you haven't already, please subscribe and turn on notifications, join the membership stream as well, and enjoy the encore together with us!
こうして、えー、初めてのね、えー、生誕3Dライブを迎えることができたのも、いつも応援してくださっている皆さんのおかげです。
that we were able to hold our very first 3D birthday live like this is all thanks to everyone who always supports us.
日々ビビが活動できているのは、ビビ民の支えがあるからです。
The reason Vivi is able to be active day by day is because of the support of Vivid-min.
え、そして、え、改めてですね、この生誕祭、もう準備期間結構ずっと長かったんですけど、その中ずっと支えてくださって、協力してくれた、え、尽力してくださったスタッフの皆さんも本当にありがとうございました！
And once again, for this birthday festival, the preparation period was quite long all along, but to all the staff members who constantly supported us, cooperated, and dedicated themselves, thank you so much!
こうやってたくさんね、支えてくださるスタッフの皆さんと、そしてゲストで出てくれた、ホロメンの皆さんや、いつも仲良くしてくださってるホロメンの皆さんや
To all the staff members who support us so much, the guests who appeared, and the Hololive members who are always close with us,
そして、こうして今配信を見てくださっている、そこなあなた、の存在が、今のビビの背中を押してくださってます。本当にいつもありがとうございます！
and right now, watching this stream right there—you, your existence pushes Vivi's back. Thank you all so much, as always!
なんか、ちょっと言葉で伝えるのヘタくそなんですけど、みんなの応援があるからビビはこれからも
I'm kind of clumsy at putting things into words, but because of everyone's support, Vivi will continue to
どんどんどんどん階段を登っていきたいと思います！みんな、ずっとずっとついてきてね！
keep climbing the stairs higher and higher! Everyone, keep following along with me forever!
それでは、全員で応援しましょう！
With that, let's all cheer together!
せーの！うー、びび！またね！
Ready, set! Woo, Vivi! See you later!
大好きなvividへ、緊張で震える膝、支えてくれてありがとう！みんながvividをアイドルにしてくれたよ！どんな困難でもみんながいれば乗り越えていける！！これからもずっとそばにいて♡
To my dearest vivid, thank you for supporting my trembling knees! Everyone made vivid an idol! With everyone, we can overcome any hardship!! Stay by my side forever♡